Hello Hello Friends Health Insurance This is
Doctor I am Sumit Bhandariya
Thank you very much for watching this video
Today's topic is Hey Jogiya
Sanjivani Policy Look we have been getting questions about this policy for a
long time,
many people were saying that
make a video on it We have already
given a lot of information about it on our website You want this policy on our website
In the description of this video you can find the length
point health insurance yeh.com By sliding
you will get the link directly You
want what is the premium of the policy and
you
can also see the details of the policy in a bridge If you want then
you can click on us anytime health
insurance is gmail.com We will
send you a copy of whichever company you ask
Let's start with what is this policy
Why was this policy made in the first place It was
running in a room with IRDA for many years that when a consumer is
going to talk about the policy then ABC
he is going to different companies,
different policies of different companies  It is different from the media, if we
put products of different Apollo companies, then this is a very simple, normal
consumer, an average consumer, he has so much
knowledge of 30 domains that he
can understand the nuances of the policy. The
premium of each policy is different, each policy has different features, so
somewhere or the other, it used to fall on the insurance agent
that he is selling the product of the consumer's choice.
In many SM companies, there would be a better
product for the same consumer at a
lower premium, that is, according to his need.
Many Wasim companies had a better product,
but due to any reason, the shares of the company get
contested, in any reason, many
times the same company is promoting the same product, in
which the company or the agency itself is getting
more benefit. See,
each company Arjun is running its own business,
I am not saying that it is wrong, so with this ribbon the
consumer does not have a choice, the policy holder does
not have a choice, first of all they are saying to
send it to only one company,
what can you policy holder do,
meet the agents of five companies and
send the policy to them and compare them.  If you
look a little on Google or
watch some video, then 15 days are
spent in gathering information about this, after that
nothing comes out, he gets
so much information that because of its line, he is
not able to digest it, so
practically
he is not in a position to take a decision, so to
solve this kind of problem,
many years ago, the idea was thought of
making a standard product,
so it was recently introduced in January
that Star Cut will make it and
all the companies in Apple have
launched it, but practically some companies had
launched it before that, so the name of the product is
Arogya Sanjeevani Policy and
we can also call it a technically standard
health insurance plan, that is, if you
buy a policy from any company, the
end product that you will get from any insurance company, that
is, the product will be
hundred percent the same in all the companies,
now normally when we used to buy a policy earlier, there were
two things in it, the
basic structure of the policy was done, that is,
how can you
buy the basic policy from any company
Structure Likexy all the best policy you
take if that company starts the
policy, you will not get anything for the first 30 days, in the
first 2 years there are some compulsory meeting to
attend and from 15 to 15 years for diseases, thirdly
when you are getting the policy, if you already have any
disease then there is a waiting period of West Indies,
now in some expensive policy
it is for two years meeting, in normal
companies meeting for one year and the companies which have been updated,
even today they have this requested
meeting period of 14 years only, so this was an
extended term which all the companies had to keep, the
benefit of this fact was
that if you get a claim for any thing then
you will get it cleared
or not, this
happens with some instruction and its
process depends on it, if you will get the claim then you will not get it, if
you get relief then you will get it in all the companies, if you will not get it then you will get it in
all the companies, if you will not get it then you will
not get it in any, now the
second lesson was that there would be
value added services in the policy, that is, like
1GB RAM, 2GB RAM and 4GB RAM in the mobile
Different types of products with 4GB RAM
are available, the processors may be different, the
camera quality may be different, but the
basic function of the phone was to make
calls from one place to another, so Idea did the same thing, with the
insurance
product, some things will be available and
some will not be available, all this is
agreed upon by the company, the second thing will be whether there
is a valid feature or not, and
like if you are getting the health insurance checkup done
at the beginning of the policy, or not, if you have got
your policy done under Tiwari underwriting, then you will get a free
health checkup or not,
how much bonus are you getting, these are some
concepts like Sanjay, if
you have not taken the restoration recharge, then it is possible that
some company is giving a discount,
if you have not taken it for three-four years, then
you may be
giving a health checkup under that condition, so these are value
added services, that is, what you are getting in the package,
basic structure and valid
services, the services are different for every company,
due to which its premium was different,
so what did Idea do, it is basic
structure and elevated service policy  They
say benefits, they were made same on
Friday, so if you want to know the
main information of this policy in a very detailed manner, then within the next 2
minutes, you
can see them on this side with this video, there we will
cut a princess, meaning the feature is this
policy, now there is some mixed dry in this policy
that whenever you clean in this policy,
you will get only 95%, that is, there is a co-
payment of 5%, this is the
biggest problem in this policy, second thing if
you take this policy today,
because a new product is launched, the maximum co-payment
in this policy is
always 5 lakhs, so take this post, if a
person lives in Nagpur, is a young family, has
less money, then it is possible that he has taken a policy,
but if a person lives in Mumbai, then there is nothing
there today, so
a concept comes here that this
policy has co-payment and in it,
value added services are limited, no
claim bonus is available for limited, there are
not many features in it, it is a
simple policy, there are some negative points
It is clearly mentioned in the policy
as you can see on the side also, so now a
concept comes that it is a very simple
product like the products used to be
20 years ago with Shahzada, this romantic limit,
a small bonus is also given and on top of that there is an
additional problem of work no payment,
so now let us consider whether we
should think about taking this policy
or not, which is a very simple benefit
that some companies have reduced its premium,
you will get a SIM card,
some companies have given a discount of 20% from the market,
see you can take that policy,
that is, if you got it for Rs. 10,000, it is
possible that in some company you got it for Rs. 8000 only, so
simple but you can get
everything in some company, that is, if someone has a
very limited budget, then you can get a parlor
seat, but keep this in mind that you will
never get 100%, the second important
thing which is to be seen in it is what is
my
medical condition in the city where I am living  According to that, is
this product suitable for me or not,
we always talk simply
that if someone takes consultancy from us after thinking about it, then
what do we do, but in reality
we see its growth,
right now it is checked that it has the
exact requirement, so many times the
person does not know that he does
not have information about some things,
like he is having some meeting problem, so according to that
many times he has to give more
information, so we do this process, so
many times in some case, as far as the
main parathas are premium, then perhaps in that
particular case, I can
suggest to some person that let's go for some of them, it is
better to keep this, which is market
tender for Rs. 12000, and
you will get this product for Rs. 10,000, its
premium is a little bit, but
in any case you have to keep in mind that if your
age is 50, 5560, 6570, then this
product can be there, there is nothing like that, but  It is
free but still it is okay, so those
whose premium is a little less
can think about taking this policy,
right, so default such a policy from a
company whose premium is low, you can actually buy a
policy within your budget,
secondly, if someone has
financial constraints even with low premium, that
I have to pay a train, then
naturally he will not understand the benefits of this policy,
so remember, this policy has only
one plan, you have to
do it blindly, you do not need any advice,
you can buy this policy from anywhere,
you will get the same product, these are very
good things, it is subject to, the
only problem is that there is a particular mini
statement, the policy
is good for only a few people and so, for example, if a person is 45 years old, then
what happens to him normally is that he gets some clear stress,
some job responsibilities are too
much, some new Health India
Central, we have its property, so
normally at that age, no one is free to take a decision at home.  If it is
included then
leave it and see if you want a cover of 10, 15, 20
lakh rupees then there is no need to search for this policy
for parents, I do not strongly recommend it because of
which policy the bonus is. The bonus is very less today and today
we decided to take the policy, then you will get a huge 55
percent bonus which is nothing as of today's date.
Nowadays, if you start getting a bonus of 50 percent to 1000
percent, then in
comparison to that, this is a small 1GB RAM type
phone, so it is very good for some,
but do not
keep it too much like this. Yes, someone can sell you a product by saying that
this product is very
good, it is not an IIT graduate, it is not
something that I can say, this product has
tremendous validated features, it is
a simple product, if you like it,
you can buy it. If you
need any information about the product, then
its complete information is given below in the description of this video and if
you click inside it, you will get all the
details there.  You will get one thing, still you have to keep
one thing in mind that whenever there is
a time of corona going on nowadays, then
whenever you add transparency in it, like
Sanjeevani policy for shares, bike, then
its cover of corona will
start only after 30 days, so in these days if
someone is facing any financial
problem, then they closed their eyes and bought
5 kg, otherwise 99% wait, I will
not recruit for this policy, well,
we were getting a lot of questions from you like,
term insurance,
mutual funds, etc. Many types of people
consult us, we ask every question,
so we accept marriage directly and
type with some financial planner, so
what serial is running in today's date, what are the
different mutual fund equity products in that planning industry,
then how
important is Vishnu, what is his race, can there be any
deficiency in it or what things
should be kept in mind, there are many such topics
which are covered every week  If we do 2 episodes together, then
we are not promoting anything in it.
We do not sell any product other than health insurance.
We do not promote obscene or any
product. So,
if you need information about anything, then
you can watch those videos. These are
very relevant, you can get it activated there.
You can watch it. There will be a discussion,
maybe you have something to say from that. If
you need any
kind of validation in the next video, then first like it
and share it with your friends. If
you want to give this message option, then I will send
you a mail or
WhatsApp to you in future. We will definitely make some
improvements. You will make more videos according to some fashion. So,
thank you very much. There
is a crore of time to watch this video. Please
maintain social distancing and
take full care of your family. Thank you very much.